# Juan David Tamayo Q

#### Personal data

20/04/1989, Colombian C.c.: 1053794456

#### Contact

(+57) 3217383757 jdtamayoq@gmail.com Linkedin,

# Languages

Spanish (Native), English (intermediate)

#### Skills

Python, Matlab, Linux, R, Power BI, SQL, G Suite, Git, GitHub

#### Courses

Machine Learning with Python Recol. y exploración de datos Machine Learning with Big Data Mathematics for Machine Learning: Linear Algebra and Multivariate Calculus. Deep Learning for Business Business Intel. con Power BI Python: Comprehensions, Lambdas y Manejo de Errores curso profesional de Scrum

#### **Groups** Currently

Smart Data Analysis Systems Group (SDAS)

**Past** 

Soft and Hard Applied Computing (SHAC) Percepción y Control Int. (PCI)

## References

#### Diego Hernán Peluffo-Ordóñez

President of SDAS group Phone: (+593) 992463728

#### Juan Bernardo Gómez Mendoza

Proffesor Universidad Nacional Phone: (+57) 301 2443806

#### **Eder Arley León Gómez**

ARUS - ing. Data Science Phone: (+57) 317 5874629

# **Profile**

Currently, he is passionate about 2D, 3D image and data processing with comprehensive experience in acquisition, preprocessing, and post-processing image data. His primary research interests are deep learning and machine learning applied to data, signal, image, and video analysis for medical and industrial applications.his topics interest encompasses kernel-based and spectral methods, multi-expert methods, and high dimensional data.

### **Awards**

♦ PhD scholarship ♦ Best Master's average ♦ Innovative social entrepreneurship ('Enlinea')

# **Experience**

2021	Teaching professor of software engineering at TDEA	ıa
2021	Professor Mision Tic 2022  Concept of python from basics, thoroughly, and categorically. Example and practice approach. Help in any problem that occurs while coding, at the spot	
2020	Machine learning Internship  Projects: ♦ Bag of Multiples Experts (BoE): simulations of multiples annotator using ENN ♦ The MI methods that are suitable for multi-label classification	

2016-2020 Research 3D data processing applied to medical issues. Universidad Nacional de Colombia **Projects:** ♦ 3d to 2.5d projection using curvature, depth and point accumulation. ♦

Dental diagnostic using a ML approach. ♦ Dental segmentation.

2016-2017 Professor digital image processing Universidad Nacional de Colombia **Projects:** ♦Banana detection based on color and texture features. ♦ Multispectral

images in remote sensing, ♦ Drowsinnes detection ♦ Text segmentation and others.

2012 **Assistant Data Scientist** Universidad Nacional de Colombia Range image registration software using touch interfaces. "Software de registro de

imágenesde rango usando interfaces táctiles -40301037215".

# **Education**

2017-Currently	PhD candidate	Universidad Nacional de Colombia
	The doctoral research is applied to digital dentis	try: Medical tools to improve ortho-
	dontic diagnosis using machine learning techniques and deep learning.	
2013-2015	Master of Engineering - Industrial Automation	Universidad Nacional de Colombia

2013-2015 **Master of Engineering - Industrial Automation** 

Thesis: A Contribution to Semi-automatic Segmentation of Point Clouds.

2007-2012 **Electronic engineering** Universidad Nacional de Colombia

Mapi: Advanced Topics in Computer Vision, Multivariate analysis and numerical ana-

# **Publications**

Multi-Expert methods evaluation on Financial and Economic Data: Introducing Bag of Experts

International Conference on Hybrid Artificial Intelligence Systems

2015 Emerging Trends in Image Processing, Computer Vision and Pattern Recognitions Elservier Book

Chapter 28: "Semi-automatic teeth segmentation in 3d models of dental casts using a

hydrid methodology"

2014 IPCV'14 - The 2014 International Conference on Image Processing

"Image Segmentation Techniques Applied to Point Clouds"

# Additional information

Chair: Workshop in Machine learning: supervised and unsupervised techniques, Volunteer in AIESEC team leader, Teacher Mision Tic 2022, SDASer and a Passion for Science and Technology. Personal links: Linkedin.